[Music]
w
hello good evening good day everybody I
hope you're all doing great welcome to
the latest episode of the askab show we
are almost reaching episode 200 this is
episode 197
so I hope you're all doing great let me
see who all is in attendance on the live
chat as always let's see we have alok B
mangka ban Arian Chan parav kundu Ayan
Ali prajal patil elshin Lohi omik ruir
salanki shat AA Ashok Kumar nagura vinit
Sangle
ragavendra geopolitical dub X XM y mus
Zed mus
Matrix pramesh rakasi
rajaj uh Captain cool uwal Gupta
surender Gupta haray zubon isang
revolutionary Indian Dr suryakant dager
Banda Panda aradya and aan aan shagun
Chopra impermanence random skull hello
pratim de vikrant marate Martian an
Sharma Groot one WRV 1313 niharika Gupta
Vladimir chavda
vinit sa pramesh Amisha Mishra hello
vinit Savant samit statement minini
Rahul dun amol Jane revolutionary Indian
once again we see uh three ways S2 pruma
deep Deepak deepank
jangid barav kundu Santa Claus is here
space KGB agent is here arush Sinha even
RAF rapic Amal James
sidhart Singh Raj purohit Karan Singh
Arian in sksm sairan pram Roy vinod
Krishna Gupta uh Shadow anit cile Shan
okay let me stop quickly now copile
harita and everybody else okay so good
evening good day everybody wherever you
are wherever in the world you are
watching this thank you so much for
being on the live stream so I'm going to
take questions that you have asked in
the comments I'm going to take a bunch
of those and then I will take more
questions from the live chat once those
are over that's what we will do today um
ainka says why are my chats not seen
well I'm seeing your chat so there you
are so there's no
issue uh so with that said let's see
let's see what are the questions that we
have for
today uh question number one what is
question number one it is by Prine
gapar PM Narendra Modi will visit
president Wladimir Putin in Russia next
month what would be the key Focus the
key Focus would be the entire gamut of
bilateral relations between India and
Russia whether it's economic relations
whether it is
energy oil and gas whether it is a
defense
cooperation whether it is the sale
possible perhaps sale or or transfer of
Technology of fighter jet engines
whether it is various strategic Affairs
when in which we have significant areas
of
convergence all of that see India and
Russia we have always had what's what we
call a privileged relationship a special
relationship we are not formal allies in
the sense that we don't have any uh
formal treaty that establishes us as
allies for example you can have a treaty
of mutual self-defense if somebody
attacks me you will come to my rescue if
somebody attacks you I'll come to your
rescue that's that's a formal Treaty of
Alliance military Alliance kind of but
we don't have any such thing with Russia
but we have a very very longstanding
relationship going back to the
1940s 1950s with Russia when the when
Russia was then the USSR so it's a
relationship that India needs to uh
place a tremendous amount of special
emphasis on and the same goes for Russia
there are very few nations in the world
that that Russia can kind of count on on
these days Russia needs as many friends
let's say as possible obviously there
are no friends in geopolitics but let's
say let's call it friendship right so
the the Russians are kind of well the
Americans would like to isolate them
totally the entire EU and NATO and most
other nations are along with the US
they're going along with that so there's
very few Nations that Russia can
actually uh count on at this uh time
when you have this uh uh this new Cold
War that's kind of broken up out cold
war
2.0 so India is kind of a bridge between
uh East and West India is kind of kind
of a bridge between the Western
Le uh us Le hegemonic Alliance and the
nations of the global South and India
has good relations with everybody more
or less so that's why India is so
important in the current context and
India is obviously a growing
economy major geopolitical power now
India so Russia needs India and India
also would like to uh work with Russia
when it comes to various areas of of
Interest there's a lot that India would
also want from Russia we would like to
have a continuing supply of uh cheap
energy oil gas whatever else which we
can which we have then been being
reselling to the West after refining it
and all I mean that's even the West is
fine with that so we're not doing
anything bad there
um uh technology fighter planes perhaps
fighter jet technology so much more um
and obviously we have to understand that
the West is not India's friend we know
the the various Shenanigans the West is
uh currently conducting against India uh
on the one hand they would like to say
that India is is um the US India
relationship is uh one of the most
consequential relationships of the 21st
century on the other hand they would
like to they're in the process of
accusing India of attempting
assassinations of terrorists on us soil
but those terrorists are obviously
American citizens so that's bad
then U and they are harboring all kinds
of anti-india
elements among the Western Nations
especially the anglosphere Nations the G
the FIS Nations especially Canada these
days khalistani terrorists and so on
and much more and we know what they are
trying in Burma and Manipur right that
that hurts India directly so we have to
understand that the West is not India's
friend the West would like to use India
for its own purposes and then dispose of
India so India needs to know the India
obviously I'm sure understands this the
government of India is very capable they
understand what's going on so we need to
have as many options as possible so
everything will be discussed in Moscow
I'm not sure how long this visit will be
of Prime Minister Modi in Moscow or
wherever it is that they're going to
they're going to meet but it's I'm glad
that the yearly Summit meetings are
restarting the last Summit meeting was
in 2022 if I'm not mistaken when uh Mr
Putin came to New Delhi for just one day
for just a few hours actually and he met
with Prime Minister Modi and they had
their meeting uh it's typically a yearly
event and then in
23 was it held or was it 21 the last
time and then there was a virtual
meeting as well and then the last year
or so there was there's been no meeting
for whatever reason so I'm glad this is
restarting it's very important for India
it's very important for Russia and it is
an important relationship for the rest
of the world as well so that's the thing
there's no single point of key Focus
lots of areas of focus and everything is
going to be discussed and worked
upon okay adash Narayan rout says what
did you conclude from the debate that
happened between uh Mr Biden President
Biden and uh president Trump former
president Trump on CNN where is the US
going in the future and how will they
have their geopolitical policy look
first of all let me tell you that the
American geopolitical policy foreign
policy foreign strategy Etc never
changes doesn't matter who is the
president of the US it makes no
difference right now you have a
president who is not functional who is
cognitively not present there he is
clearly not not a functioning human
being not even
50% and his Deputy Miss Kamala Harris
is no better okay but someone's running
the country that's become very clear to
everybody now someone's still running
the country who is it so someone's
running the country there is a power
center that is completely extra
Democratic extra constitutional extra
whatever it has nothing to do with the
president of the US and the current
regime it makes no difference so the US
geopolitical policy foreign policy
military policy Etc will not change it
will make no difference who comes to
power who comes to apparent power as the
US president the real power in the US
lies somewhere else please understand
this by now it should be clear if you
have a functioning brain that the US is
a democracy only in name a two-party
system which has the same foreign policy
no matter which party comes to power and
even if the president is non-functional
the nation still runs just fine so
clearly
clear I think even the Americans are now
no no matter how brainwashed they may be
even they are beginning to realize that
something's aess over here
so the US geopolitical policy foreign
policy military policy will not change
no matter who comes to power whether
it's Trump whether it's Biden whether it
is uh Michelle Obama Michelle Michelle
Obama whoever comes to power it makes no
difference right Biden is a sock puppet
a puppet so is Miss Harris now uh the
debate I didn't I still haven't watched
it I've seen some Snippets and clips of
the
debate um and what did I conclude I the
feeling see what what was very obvious
is that Biden was drugged that's what it
looked like he was not blinking when
you're not blinking and you're so
intense you you are on something whether
it
is amphetamin or or
whatever some kind of what they call an
upper which keeps you focused and alert
well he looked like he was hyper focused
and Hyper alert and super aggressive
right no blinking and those intense
statements and just speaking robotically
and not very clear and there were times
when the memory disappeared and he was
fumbling with his words and he had no
idea what what what word to say next so
clearly the guy was on something and
clearly he's not a cognitively cog
cognitively functional human being okay
that was clear I think that was clear to
everybody even Barack Obama Biden's
former boss he was forced to tweet that
one bad debate doesn't make much of a
difference you to look at the guy's
entire career his career was in the past
okay so it's clear that uh it's clear
even the Democrats are admitting that
Biden lost the debate catastrophically
it was a catastrophic defeat for Biden
the debate Trump even Trump said that I
have no idea what the guy said just now
you know he he said that at least once
so what is my sense after watching this
debacle of a debate by the sitting
president of the US I think that he is
not going to be the presidential
candidate come November or whenever the
elections are whenever the election is
uh I think eventually the Democrats will
uh pull him from the race uh by then it
will be pretty clear that he's in
terminal cognitive decline there's no
coming back from that he needs to be in
a retirement home and be in Comfort
instead of being put into these
situations uh so I think I think Biden
will not be the presidential candidate
when the election happens I don't think
Miss Kamala Harris also will be the
presidential
candidate I think she will also pull out
in
in in in a s in a display of solidarity
with her boss with her well nominal boss
Mr Biden and it could be somebody like
Michelle Obama who come who maybe the
presidential candidate or perhaps
Hillary Clinton if they want to put her
or whoever the powers to be decide
should be the presidential candidate so
the sense I'm getting is that Biden is
not going to be the guy who will be the
Democratic nominee for president in
November it'll be somebody else entirely
maybe Hillary Clinton maybe um Michelle
Obama or maybe who knows Dwayne The Rock
Johnson Oprah Winfrey who knows maybe
some actor actress they them she her
whatever yeah that's that's the sense
I'm getting let's see if I'm right or if
I turn out to be wrong and it's Biden
who stands who's still running for
elections for for president in November
this year let's
see okay Prine garti Gap partti says
have you seen the Sha Ryan show a couple
of weeks back in which Sarah Adams
apparently a former CIA targeter agent
whatever was invited and she commented
on targeting killings of Pakistani
terrorists by unknown gunmen what's your
take on that well I haven't seen the
episode but I have seen two minute you
know uh clip from that in which she is
saying that the Indian government is
paying the Taliban 10 million million
dollars or something and the Taliban and
and the supreme leader of the Taliban is
under Indian protection Indian agents
and soldiers or whatever are protecting
him are offering him prot protection and
apparently India is paying 10 million or
something to the Taliban to carry out
targeted killings of Pakistani
terrorists in Pakistan that sort of
thing that's what she claims what do I
make of it well lady show me the
evidence I can say whatever I want I can
say that I am the descendant of of
Emperor keska well anybody can make any
claim what's the evidence yeah so it's
all he say it's nice it it's it's
it makes uh well it it draws attention
if you are a podcaster and you you have
somebody coming in as your guest and
that guest makes these incredible claims
Fantastical claims hey great for my
podcast I'm going to get views yeah
millions of views all the Indians and
all the pakistanis and whoever else is
are going to come and descend on my show
and look for it look for that that that
particular segment where the lady speaks
about this whatever allegations she's
making my point is what's the evidence
has she provided any evidence no she has
not anybody can say anything so I'm not
buying what she's saying but what is she
trying to do is she really a CIA agent
let's say that she is a c former CIA
agent targeter whatever you want to call
her okay so what is she trying to
achieve what are the possible things she
may be trying to achieve first of all
she may be trying to draw attention to
herself and become famous that's one
thing uh but you talk about India
Taliban Etc in the US you the Americans
aren't really interested in these
matters
they're interested in Russia they're
interested in Ukraine they're interested
in Israel India is not very high on the
uh priorities when it comes to interests
you know among viewers so in that case
she's not really trying to be famous
because that won't make her famous if
she makes statements about Israel and
Palestine or Russia Ukraine that's what
will make her really famous in the US so
she's talking about India and Taliban
Pakistan and alleging that India is
paying money to the Taliban to take out
Pakistani terrorists in Pakistan so
she's not trying to be famous here she's
trying to put out a narrative of some
kind so this seems to be in line with
the recent wave of claims by the
Americans in the west even the
Australians that India has been doing
certain things the Canadians claim that
India took out Indian assassins took out
a terrorist in Canada they say he was a
Canadian citizen Let It Be terrorist
whatever the Americans the American
government has claimed that India has TR
tried to assassinate an American
Terrorist in America
and they even had uh uh somebody
extradited from some from some Eastern
European country which country was it I
forget Hungary
something and now they're claiming that
India is carrying out proxy targeted ass
assassinations of Pakistani terrorists
in Pakistan VI the Taliban so overall it
looks like they're trying to make India
they're trying to paint India as a rogue
rogue Nation a nation that you know
carries out all these illegal edly
illegal activities and assassinations
and and targeted killings and and so on
so they're trying to kind of paint India
in the same light that they paint Russia
and North Korea and Iran with okay and
what do they achieve by doing that they
get to arm twist India behind closed
doors and during diplomatic negotiations
and extract whatever pounds multiple
pounds of Flesh they want to
extract or maybe they want to make Mr
Narendra Modi look
I don't know we have to consider all the
all the different possibilities maybe
they want maybe they think that they
have put too much pressure on Indian let
the Indians look look a little good now
let let the uh people of India feel that
the government is doing the right thing
I don't know I'm just guessing okay I'm
just putting out various possibilities
some are more probable some are
significantly less probable I'm just
saying so I don't know first of all my
point is I don't believe this lady okay
sah Sarah Adams whatever
she has provided no evidence for the
claims she has made so when you make
claims when you make a claim the burden
of proof is on
you right when you make an allegation
when you make a claim when you put forth
a new
Theory the burden of proof is on the
person who makes the claim makes the
allegation puts forth the new Theory
whatever so she has not fulfilled that
part of the bargain she has not provided
any proof so that's why I do not need to
take her
seriously what can be claimed without
evidence can be dismissed without
evidence please understand that what can
be claimed what is claimed without
evidence can be dismissed without
evidence so I don't take this
seriously okay two questions out of many
I'm sure ronak mondal and Sonia
condal why is North Korea sending troops
to fight against Ukraine do you think
that North Korea that with North Korea
sending troops to the Russia Ukraine war
it might escalate the situation further
towards a World War okay what's the deal
so Mr Putin recently visited North Korea
for the first time in almost a quarter
Century almost 25 years and he had a
very warm uh series of interactions with
Mr Kim Mr Kim Jong Un and the relations
within with the two nations are clearly
great they made a series of uh they came
to a series of agreements they seem to
have signed some kind of uh military
Alliance kind of treaty if somebody
attacks me you you help me out if
somebody attacks you I help you out that
sort of thing that's kind of a NATO like
thing you know uh and there is some
speculation now that North Korea maybe
maybe on the verge of sending military
personnel
to to assist Russia in the Ukraine
conflict
and uh I'm not sure how true that is but
let's say it's going to happen and the
question is are these military personnel
that North Korea may be sending will
they be actual combat troops or will
they be in a different capacity maybe in
construction maybe in infrastructure
maybe Communications maybe something
like that maybe
engineering so if they are sending
Personnel it doesn't mean that they're
going to be in a combat capacity maybe
it's a different capacity maybe it's
engineering maybe it's Communications
maybe is technical support whatever
right we don't know yet now let's assume
that this sending soldiers to fight in
the front lines the first of all the
question is why would North Korea do
that maybe because they've signed the
treaty and right now Russia is at War so
let's
uh you know let's hit the ground running
in this treaty and let let's send let's
say a th 2,000 troops to to Russia's Aid
that sort of thing well then if it's a
small number of troops that North Korea
will be sending then it doesn't make a
tremendous amount of a difference
and even if they're going to send let's
say 50,000 troops 100,000 troops which
is a massive commitment massive assume
that hypothetical scenario is true
assume for now for the sake of argument
even then what big difference does it
make Russia has way more troops than
that and North Korea is not one of the
big geopolitical powers that can unleash
a World War okay nuclear war how many
nukes do they do do we think they have
maybe 20 10 15 20 let's 30 is that
enough to blow up the world no so that's
not something that triggers the world
war unless it it sets off a train
reaction that then brings Russia's nukes
or China's nukes into play which could
be the trigger for a World War because
even if we talk about China China itself
alone may not have enough nukes to
trigger a gigantic
war or Global apocalypse to have a
global apocalypse you need in excess of
1,000 nuclear bombs being detonated okay
we never want this to happen we just
talking the you know hypotheticals here
we we don't want that to happen but
that's what we call a World War in which
significant amounts of Nar exchange you
know nuclear exchange we don't want that
ever because that is a that is a
disaster scenario it's it's
apocalypse uh so I don't think if if
North Korea sends troops to fight
alongside Russia in the Ukraine conflict
I don't think it's going to be it's
going to be definitely an
escalation uh but first of all uh not
sure if it's if it's happening if it's
combat troops they're sending and
secondly if they will not send too many
troops and even if they send a decent
amount of amount of troops it doesn't
change the situation on the ground too
much so overall it's it's a slight
escalation but not a huge escalation
slight to medium escalation not a huge
escalation the Americans and NATO have
have been talking about sending French
troops and whatever else troops on to
the ground to fight the Russians they've
already approved you know sending using
NATO weapons and ammunitions and arms
against Russia so they are ratcheting up
the escalation ladder aren't they so
obviously the Russians will also uh pay
them back in kind so we are seeing
escalation increased increasing
escalation on both sides and that's not
good for the world uh because yeah
Ukraine is a is a very dangerous
flasho so overall that's where we are uh
it's definitely an escalation if North
Korea sends troops to fight alongside
Russia it's not a huge escalation but
it's an escalation nevertheless which
brings us slightly closer to what we
never want to see a nuclear exchange
between Russia and the us we hope it
doesn't
happen Okay Raj Chopra says you've
claimed that this decade will be the
decade of the pandemic in a very old
podcast how far is this prediction
holding up till now okay the podcast
you're referring to is a podcast that I
must have done in 2021 or something with
ranir labadia must be there on his
channel and in this podcast I recall
saying that the 2020s could be the
decade of the virus
okay so it we have to be
very precise when we make claims we have
to use the correct words I have said
that the 2020s could be the decade of
the virus I did not say it this decade
will be the decade of the pandemic okay
so that's one correction there now how
far is this prediction it's not a
prediction I said something could be I
don't I didn't say this will happen I'm
making a prediction in this decade this
will happen I said the 2020s could be
the decade of the virus that is not a
prediction that's a hypothetical I don't
make predictions I'm not in the business
of making predictions I'm not an
astrologer or a geopolitical astrologer
or whatever you want to call it I I talk
about probabilities and and
possibilities I said it's possible that
this decade could be the decade of the
virus uh because at the time when we
were we made this podcast you know uh
new variants the Omicron variant had
come out and various other o you know
variant of the Wuhan Corona virus had
come out there were multiple waves
multiple waves of lockdowns and multiple
waves of various mutants of the virus
coming out so at that time I said this
decade could be the decade of the virus
now how far is that holding up right now
it's it's not quite holding up the media
still tries to claim some new waves
coming up and all once in a while but I
think we are beyond that so I am very
glad to say that thus far it's not
coming out to be true
okay the possibility that this decade
could be the decade of the virus thus
far by in in Midway through through 2024
about three years after I had that I did
that podcast thus far it's not come true
any of that new viruses or whatever
there's been word you know news of some
new viral outbreak here or there but
nothing serious what was it swine flu
was it was it chicken Aven flu something
I heard a few months ago
I'm glad it's
disappeared I do not want to see a
decade of the virus I seriously don't
want to see that the Wuhan virus
pandemic was was more than enough it was
so immensely incredibly painful for the
world for India especially for those
people who are financially not well off
it was terrible for them it was ruinous
for small businesses in Industries we
don't want to see that again so thus far
it's it doesn't look like it may it will
happen Okay but you never know and I I
hope that that
hypothetical scenario that this decade
could be the decade of the virus I I
seriously hope that it doesn't happen
and thus far it doesn't look like it's
happening but we got about five and a
half years left to go for this decade so
fingers crossed okay fingers crossed we
don't want that to happen maybe this
will be the decade of decade of AI and
AI will turn out to be the biggest virus
of all who knows who knows AGI
ASI you know what by now I'm sure they
have AGI artificial general intelligence
uh in the labs uh at the disposal of the
US military the US government I'm sure
they have it by now maybe even ASI
artificial super intelligence what we
are seeing is merely the tip of the
iceberg that's possible so now that you
have that why do you need to fiddle with
viruses
you already tested a few aren't you okay
next
oh feminist Slayer says what are the
factors contributing to the frequent
instances of infrastructure failures
such as collapsing bridges falling
Billboards Etc in modern times in
contrast ancient structures like temples
and pyramids have withstood the test of
time remaining intact for thousands of
years what design and construction
elements did ancient builders in
corporate that are lacking in
contemporary infrastructure development
okay now let me answer the question and
I am not going to refer to any you know
any X incident or Y incident in a city
or B City or Z City okay I'm just going
to give you a
general principle that when such things
happen in a country no matter how big or
small it is it typically points towards
uh uh the fact that there is corruption
in the country okay a certain level I
don't know to what level high low
whatever but when you have
infrastructure uh failures collapses of
bridges or collapses of flyovers of or
collapses of buildings and so on so
forth in a country and if that happens
frequently enough it kind of tells you
that there is something wrong in the
system and maybe the system is corrupt
what do you mean by
corruption what is the definition of
corruption corruption a system is
corrupt when it is doing something that
it is not designed to do it is doing
something else it is it is deviating
from its stat stated purpose and
objective and it is doing something that
is not supposed to be its objective that
is a corruption that is corruption and
generally corruption in any country
let's say a hypothetical country X if
you have corruption in the system it
means that the officers or or the
officials in the system let's say the
administrative process or whatever it is
they are siphoning off funds and putting
those funds in their own accounts in
their own Pockets typically okay in any
let's say some hypothetical African
dictator dictator ship country okay so
that's typically how it is the dictator
and his his Entourage and and the
officials in the government they are
siphoning off public funds which are
supposed to be used for the construction
of flyovers and bridges and whatever and
they are putting that in their own bank
accounts so let's say a $100 million
were were sanctioned for a certain
bridge then maybe $20 million were used
and 80 million were were were
misappropriated so then obviously you
will have inferior materials that are
used and and insufficient concrete and
all that which after a certain period of
time will contribute to the collapse of
that particular piece of infrastructure
okay completely hypothetical African
country I'm talking about I'm not
talking about any specific event or
location so let's say in Africa
something like this happens it means
probably that in that hypothetical
country there is corruption that's what
I would say and in Africa you have
something like the pyramids in North
Africa Northeast Africa in Egypt
misser uh pyramids that have stood for
thousands of years so I can assure you
that the kings of that time the Pharaohs
were definitely uh they had ured there's
no corruption because those structures
still stand and looks like they'll stand
for another few thousand years unless
humans fiddle with them too much um and
obviously those are stone structures
today you have concrete uh you you have
concrete mixed with sand and then you
have to cure it or whatever you to
expose it to water for a certain amount
of time and so on so uh depending on the
quality of materials you use it will the
structure will last a certain amount of
time on average uh so we don't we don't
longer using durable materials or super
durable materials like Stone which is
why uh today's structures don't last
that
long um Whenever there is large amount
of rainfall in any part of the world and
if it's a corrupt country or a third
world nation let's say somewhere in the
equatorial belt in let's say in
hypothetically a country in Africa then
you will see lots of collapses of
buildings happening in in that region
right more frequent than usual so that's
what I will say that's the general
principle that when in any hypothetical
country you have such things happening
more frequently than is normal then it
kind of points to the fact that there is
corruption in that country and that is
obviously something that needs to be
looked at and corrected if the
government has the uh wherewithal to do
that or if they have the coones to do
that that's what I can
say coones
Cara okay next question anabeth Jackson
says who funded the ltte Ah that's a
blast from the past ltte Liberation
Tigers of Tamil ilum who funded the LT
where the diaspora of Sri Lanka tamils s
Rich that they could fund the training
and weapons for hundred thousands of
people for over 26 years look this is a
whole Pandora's Box very long
story but uh to make a long story short
like I am fond of saying
apparently uh if you recall that there
were negotiations going on between the
ltte under vuil prakaran and the Sri
Lankan governments of various Sri Lankan
governments and who was mediating this
negotiations I think it was the
government of
Norway now what does this little tiny
little insignificant little Nation
called Norway what business do they have
negotiating this interesting isn't it
and yet they were part of the
negotiations they were the mediators in
all this even when the final battles
were happening in 2008 and let's not
talk about how Gastly those battles were
uh apparently the
Norwegians I think Norwegians were kind
of was it Denmark was it Norway was it
SW Sweden I think it was
Norway uh ltte mediation let's let's ask
our good friend Google okay because my
memory isn't that sharp uh LT tte
mediation uh Norway was
it Norway Norwegian Conflict Management
approach in Sri
Lanka norw yes it was Norway for sure it
was Norway so I was correct my my my
my memory was correct it was Norway that
was mediating so what business does this
small little insignificant country
geopolitically um not relevant country
have in this major
conflict well maybe Norway is somebody's
proxy Norway is a Western Country right
it's part of Western Europe the Western
World and we also have to understand
that the Sri Lankan Tamil diaspora is
not a rich Di ipora okay some of them
may be rich but most of them are not
very rich so first of all it's a small
diaspora and secondly they're not very
prosperous or
wealthy so how who funded the LTT all
this
time and now to understand that kind of
we have
to understand this thing that not a lot
of people may be aware of the founder or
or the leader of the ltte
Mr vuil
prabhakaran he was not
Hindu you know we think of the ltte as a
Hindu uh
organization because they were all Sri
Lankan tamils tamils are typically
Hindu and most Canon F in the LTT were
obviously
Hindus but the leadership was not Hindu
Mr prabakar and his family were
Christians they you know that well now
you do so that would in that would Point
towards the involvement of certain
organizations certain
countries um something to do with
religion and so on so forth
so I guess if you want to understand
what was happening you can start by
looking along those lines all
right okay G of K kiaser says I want to
start learning reading about true
history Indian scriptures Vic literature
where do I start from okay that's a lot
of a very very vast field that you have
spoken about Indian history Indian
scriptures where the literature even Vic
literature is tremendously vast what
about the rig how do you
start reading or or learning or reading
like you say the Riga well why don't we
do a Google Search right let me show you
so this is how you do some research I'm
going to show you you go to Google you
say rig vea online and let's say what
Google has to
say so there is a Vic Heritage portal
there is a wisdom lib there is Riga
trans uh there is RVA index okay let's
see sacred
text what is this website like okay it
is a translation by rth Griffith
1896 so if you look at this let's say we
look at the book nine of the Riga and
let's start with the first one
so uh hymn one
so it's an English translation by this
gentleman called RAF Griffith who did
the translation or published it in
1896 okay so this is an English
translation that you get over here you
get a full translation of the entire rig
weather but let's say you don't want to
see this sacred text then you could go
to wisdom lib and you could cross
reference the sacred text translation
with the translation that you have here
I think it's the same one oh this is a
different one
1866 so you have a whole number of
suktas in book
one book two book three book four book
five
s okay let's say we go to sukta one of
book nine and look at this so over here
you have a Sanskrit schloka
and uh no close that and you have an
English translation and then there's
some kind of commentary so this is
another alternative that you have what
else do we have let's see then there is
a Vic Heritage portal I will open that
then there is
uh the penguin Classics uh version of
the rig with oh God vendy doniger I will
not recommend this at all so I'm going
to ignore this um then there is the
complete rig witha in English on the
internet
archive and let's see how long it takes
to
open and uh who's the author of this I'm
not sure but you know my point is this
is the RAF Griffith translation
okay the point is then there is a r with
deag with transl transliteration and so
on so forth here you have that so all
these PDF files my point is if you
really want to learn if you want to
really want to study this is kind of
where you
start uh I don't think any of these
translations is entirely accurate but
that's the best you have or you could
learn Sanskrit and or you could you
could acquire a rig with a ation into in
which is in Hindi or in whatever
whatever your mother tongue is and that
would I would guess be more accurate
than a translation done by a foreigner
into English so you take that as your
reference text the Sanskrit schloka with
the Hindi translation or whatever
translation in your language that's how
you do it it's it's hard work there's no
shortcuts to this that's how you start
that's how you do it and then you can go
for the scanda puran whichever puran
whatever history whatever scripture you
will find everything online everything
available for free or you can buy books
from Amazon if you want to spend some
money and have it have an actual
physical copy of the book or you can
look up the PDFs online and have them
printed out if that works for you or
just refer to it on your device whatever
your device is that's how you do it you
got to start like this you got to do
your own let's say research but I've
shown you how to do it so You' got to
learn how to do research if you are
genuinely interested in reading the
scriptures the vas Etc that's how you do
it all right all the best
sir okay Dean aast says I wish to read
the chakti but I'm not able to find a
good Edition publ publication
translation Etc can you tell me which
one you own please I don't have any book
called The chanak Niti I have a book
called the arthashastra and here it is
this is the Penguin um penguin Classics
version of the arastra I'm not sure if
it's the this is entirely accurate
entirely correct but this is the one I
have and obviously like I just showed
with the Riga you can find a multitude
of various uh translations online you
may even find a Hindi version online or
you may find the original Sanskrit text
online if you know Sanskrit so pick up
whichever one makes sense to you which
whichever one you feel is is good for
you and go from there I have the penguin
Classics version of the earth shastra I
don't know of any book called The chakin
Niti I know these days there are authors
who write books called chakin Niti and
all that but that's not what the book
was the only text that we know was that
we are aware of that was authored by
vishnugupta chanak also known as cilia
was the
arastra there was no book called The
chakin Niti it is a creation of modern
day authors who need well who want to
sell books want to be known well good
for them I have nothing against that my
point is there is no book called The
chakin there's a book called The arastra
and I have the penguin
Classics uh version of
that McLovin says have you read the
dictator's handbook do you mean this
book The dictator's handbook yes I have
read this book and it's a it's a
reasonably good book it's a book that I
would certainly
recommend uh you read if you are
interested in how power works that's it
it throws some light on what power is
and how power works and it's not just
something that that is applicable to
dictators it's it's a the principles are
are kind of uh broad-based and kind of
universal they apply in democracies as
well the book obviously makes the
standard you know the standard claims
that that Western liberal democracy is
superior to Eastern dictatorships and
all that stuff if you are an author and
if you're an academic you want to get
published in the west and if you want to
be uh respected and recognized then you
have
to uh pay your respect at the altar of
the regime so yeah so that is there but
it's a good book so I would certainly
recommend that book if you're interested
in understanding how dictatorships work
and overall how power works and also it
it also talks the the principles it
talks about also apply are also
applicable in what we consider to be
democracies okay CK CK Chri says due to
family ties I keep traveling to Russia
quite often in the last two to three
years I have been seeing a huge huge
demographic shift in big cities of
Russia a lot of taxi drivers and other
blue color workers are from Central Asia
what could be the long-term effects of
this will this effect or affect India
Russia ties in the
future
look we know that there are at least 50
million illegal Bangladesh's Bangladeshi
infiltrators in India is that going to
affect India Russia ties or India us
ties do those illegal Bangladeshi
infiltrators who are settled who are
settled down in various ghettos and
slums all across India do they fect
India's foreign policy no but they will
affect India's demographics in the long
run unless a solution is
found even if the population is 100
million of these illegal Bangladeshi
infiltrators and settlers in India even
then they they will have no effect right
now on India's foreign policy but over
the long run over 20 30 40 years they're
going to have a significant effect on
the demography of India and the same
applies to
Russia now I don't think there's a
similar situation in Russia is
comparable to
India comparable to the kind of
Bangladeshi illegal infiltration
immigration that's happening on a daily
basis almost into India I don't think
that's happening in Russia if there are
a large number of taxi drivers blue
color workers Etc who are from Central
Asia those are most likely legal
immigrants the Russian government is
extremely strict when it comes to
Illegal immigration they will not
tolerate what we in India tolerate they
have higher standards I keep saying
right please raise your standards well
the government of India doesn't seem to
want to listen to me they have allowed
these manyy at least 50 million illegal
Bangladesh infiltrators to settle in
India and what's been done in the past
10 years to evict any of them nothing so
uh Russia has has higher standards than
India they won't allow illegal
immigration into Russia so if these
people are working in Russia I would be
pretty sure that they are legal
immigrants or legal workers so they may
have a Visa work visa or whatever or
maybe they may be immigrant settlers
legally uh that could be the case and as
we know I mean look at Russia let's go
to the map it's been a while since we
saw the map so here's the
map uh okay here's the map so Russia is
the big country here and we have the
Central Asian Nations kazakistan
usbekistan turkistan kirgistan the
Caucasus Nations like a Georgia Etc all
of these nations used to be part of the
USSR and they are still very much under
Russia's within Russia's exclusive zone
of influence almost exclusive zone of
influence and most of the people there
speak Russian as a first or second
language probably second language these
days but everybody speaks and
understands Russians Russian to a
certain extent and Russia is this very
large Nation with so many opportunities
so much work to be done there so
obviously it makes sense for people from
these Stan Nations Central Asian Nations
to seek work in Russia and the Russians
would be okay to have that
legally so I think whatever you seeing
is legal work being done by people from
Central Asia in Russia let's say they
settle down so I don't think there's
millions of them there may be tens of
thousands of them maybe tens of
thousands I don't think there's millions
of them so I don't and if you look at um
I know what you mean the demographic
changes and all that
uh I think the the Islamic population of
Russia is about
99.5% okay that is almost half of what
the Indian Islamic population is we
didn't have a census in 2020 21 whenever
but if there was a sensus I assume I
expect that the Islamic population of
India would be about 20% or more so
Russia is way way way below that it's
about half so I don't think there's any
sign significant threat in Russia of a
major demographic change of any
kind 10 20,000 Central legan workers may
not make a big difference I don't think
there's hundreds of thousands of them
that would be kind of almost like an
invasion but that's not the case so
overall I don't see a big change
happening in Russia because of this I I
feel it a similar question I think last
week or something like that um so this
is kind of along those lines but I don't
see a big change happening in Russia
demographically and it certainly will
not affect Russia's foreign policy or
the relationship of of Russia with India
in any way
whatsoever Summit statement says I'm a
Nepali but I wish I could lead India to
make it the strongest and greatest the
world has ever seen I feel that I have
the willpower to unite 1.5 billion
people to achieve a common goal uh know
what we are can I join politics if yes
how okay look I understand why you feel
this way it's because we're the same
people
the the people of India the people of
Nepal we are the same people I mean
nepales people can serve in the Indian
Armed Forces I mean how much more trust
can you can you ever see anywhere it
means I mean no Nation will allow
foreigners to join their Armed Forces
but in India the nepales people have the
right to join the Indian armed forces
and serve in the Indian Armed Forces it
tells you we the same people the same
culture the same blood same common
history everything uh and I expect
that's why you feel this way because
yeah so now the question
is you uh the nepales people can
certainly serve in the Indian armed
forces the Nepal the people of Nepal can
uh work in India without any special
permit or anything just like Indian
citizens the only thing that the people
of Nepal are not allowed to do in India
is
vote that's the only thing apart from
the nepales people can do whatever they
want they can live in India they can
work in India
do business in India I suppose and so on
so forth uh and so I expect I'm not sure
what the situation is but I expect that
it would be way easier for nepales
people for a nepales person to get
Indian citizenship because if you want
to join politics in India you have to be
an Indian Indian citizen uh and in India
you don't get citizenship by being born
on Indian Territory we don't have ju so
we have ju sanguinis which means that
one of your parents needs to have needs
to be in IND citizen so it's the right
of blood not the right of
soil now in case you don't have either
neither of your parents was an Indian
citizen in that case you can still
become a naturalized citizen in India um
and I don't think there's any law in
India that says that a naturalized
citizen of India cannot become the Prime
Minister uh it's come close to happening
once or twice perhaps before so um uh
I'm sure that if the naturalization
process must be much easier for nepales
Citizens than for let's say a citizen of
the US or whatever else so I guess what
you would have to do is first become a
citizen of India then join politics and
joining politics is its own Pathways and
all that um you would probably want need
to become a member primary member of a
of a political party whichever political
party you like the best and then you
would have to work towards the party's
objectives goals and show that you have
the the the attributes the the aptitude
the abilities to to be a good leader
strong leader and then if the political
party is a merit based party not not a
family based party then you will be able
to rise rapidly depending on your
performance and your abilities so that's
how you would do it my friend okay uh
I'm I'm very happy to see this this
comment this question and I certainly
wish you all the best we are the same
people people of India and Nepal and uh
we should work together in
everything D 12 says I recently read
about yukatan cast War for obvious
reasons the native people of yukatan
didn't know that they had they had cast
until the Christian conquest when the
Christian conquistadors informed them
that you have cast system and you have
castism and
Lia are two things every Indian of the
subcontinent should read about okay uh
that's a comment but what's the question
here okay let's talk about this entire
matter that theur 12 is talking about
what's the yukatan cast War and who are
the natives of yukatan where is yukatan
well we have to go to the map where's
the map where's the map here's the map
so we're going to go to Central
America
okay and in Central America we have the
yukatan peninsula which is part of
Mexico the capital is Merida over here
okay it's the largest I'm not sure if
the capital but it's the largest city in
yukatan and I have spoken about yukatan
multiple times before because this is
where the last giant uh meteor impact
happened meteor impact happened the fob
impact event that killed off the
non-avian dinosaurs 66 million years ago
it happened in yatan but we're talking
about much more recent history so the
natives of the yukatan region of Mexico
Mexico are the Maya people they the
they're the true natives of this region
the indigenous people of yukatan they
are called the Maya okay now these
Spaniards the Christians they conquered
this region and they imposed a certain
hierarchy on the people of this region
the hierarchy was that European people
with European blood were the were at the
top of the hierarchy they were the
elites of society then people with mixed
blood the meso I believe they're called
who were half who who were part European
and part native they were at the second
rung of the hierarchy and at the bottom
of the hierarchy you had the pure
natives the pure indigenous people the
brown skinned people CH inferior no
brown skin so that was the hierarchy and
the the the Spaniards called it ca
Casta uh and and the same system was
then superposed transposed upon India by
the British later on so the same
hierarchial system racist Hier Hier
hierarchal system was transposed by the
British upon India and then they accused
Indians of being racist against
themselves and I've spoken a lot about
this I need to put those clips up on the
channel but I'll do that sure so uh so
that is the cast system imposed by the
Europeans on the native people of
yukatan the Maya people okay so at the
lowest rung of the hierarchy of the cast
hierarchy imposed by the Europeans were
the indigenous people above that were
various levels of mixed blood people
depending on the purity of European
blood the more European blood the higher
they were on the cast hierarchy and at
the highest level the smallest minority
was the pure Europeans and they were the
ruling cast so to say in yukatan so that
was a system that the spainards imposed
upon the natives of yukatan of Mexico
the Maya people so what was this yukatan
cast War it was a rebellion in the
middle of the last of the 19th century
by the Maya people against the foreign
occupiers of Mexico it lasted about half
a century from around 1847 18 1850 all
the way into the beginning of the 20
20th
century and some of it went on until the
TW until the 1910s 1920s or something
maybe even the 1930s
until it was completely finally crushed
by the whes okay so Sy Casta is the cast
system which this Spaniards the
Europeans imposed on the
natives and limang means purity of blood
which is another racist term terminology
purity of blood means how pure is your
blood according to European standards
purest blood means completely Pure White
pure European meso 5050 means 50% native
50%
European and pure pure native means 0%
Purity pure brown pure native chii Chi
inferior no so that was the deal the
Europeans impose all these ghastly
things on the rest of the world and then
they blamed the natives for the the for
the the destruction and all the all the
problems in society that the Europeans
had created and the same thing they've
done in India but we Indians are are
accustomed we have been brainwashed by
our education system in in blaming
ourselves in self
flagellation right so that's what we
love to do
we love to blame our ancestors for
everything that went wrong in the past
10,000 years when everything went wrong
happened
under under foreign
management you know when a comp
you you know about apple right Apple
Apple computer this is Apple
so Apple computer the company was
started by Steve Jobs in the 70s 80s
whenever it was okay um so app so Steve
Jobs was in charge of apple and then
there was a coup he brought in somebody
else and that guy ousted him and for a
few years for a large number of years
Apple was run by a bunch of other people
and Steve Jobs was thrown out of his own
company and in those years the guys who
were running Apple they ran Apple almost
into B bankruptcy the company almost
want went
bankrupt so and then Steve Jobs comes
back and he revives Apple
and today it is the one of the most
valuable companies in the world my point
is
this
when Apple was on the verge of
bankruptcy who would you blame for the
problems with an apple would you blame
the
employees or would you blame the
leadership the
management when a company which was
doing very well suddenly over a period
of time goes you know reaches the The
Verge of bankruptcy who's it who's to
blame is it the common ordinary workers
who are to blame or is it the leadership
and the management who's to blame
obviously it's the leadership in the
management so India was doing
tremendously well for thousands of years
then the turkey occupation of India
happened and then the Christian
occupation of India happened over a
roughly thousand- year time period in
which time in which period of time
everything went wrong in India who are
you going to blame for this are you
going to blame the local workers the the
indigenous people or are you going to
blame the management who was running the
country the subcontinent well you have
been programmed into blaming yourselves
and your ancestors even though they were
no longer in charge of their own fate of
their own destiny so this is a lack of
critical thinking because you've not
been taught how to think because you've
been prevented from learning how to
think
critically and uh when you say things
like when I say some things like this
some people will lots of people will say
WhatsApp University WhatsApp University
grow up guys anyhow that's the
deal next question is by Santan
biswas what happened to the native
religions of and Mongolia after the
arrival of Buddhism did they die out why
didn't jism spread to Southeast Asia
unlike mainstream Vic Hinduism and
Buddhism see once again it's a good
question but it it it demonstrates that
we now think of the
Indian uh dharmic umbrella in in
terms of distinct and separate
religions so today everybody including
the person obviously who asked the
question I don't blame you all for
thinking this way because this is what
you've been taught okay so let me try
and explain that the various dharmic
schools of thought schools of
philosophical thought in India are part
are all part of the same system the
dharmic
system Boda MIM yoga
Vash shik Vidant and so on so forth
charaka these are not separate
religions these are all various schools
of thought of the same overall dharmic
system these are not separate religions
but the westerners who ruled us have
classified them as separate religions in
order to create divisions within the
Society of India and then after 1947
various Indian governments have have
made the situation
worse so today
you know when I was a kid when I was a
little kid let's say five years old J
people were not considered
non-hindus they were all a certain
specific flavor of Hinduism that's what
it was but today jism is apparently a
separate religion and today apparently
Buddhism is a separate religion so my
point is jism Buddhism Etc whatever the
dhic dharmic religions exist today I
think it's Hinduism jism Buddhism so
these three religions are are not
separate religions they are part of the
same system the dharmic system that's
Point number one now let's come to the
question Tibet and Mongolia uh we know
that the dharmic uh way of life uh has
been part of Tibet for I don't know 1500
or so years maybe almost 2,000 years um
and what happened when Dharma let's say
entered Tibet what happened to the
native religion well the native uh
system religious system whatever you
want to call it of Tibet is called bone
b o n born it still exists and it
coexists with Dharma with with Buddhism
or Hinduism or whatever you want to call
it because it's not pure what you would
call Buddhism there are elements of
Hinduism also in here if you look at
Japan it's almost 50% Hindu they worship
if you in Japan they worship every
single god and goddess that is woried in
Hinduism but the Western Scholars and
your own Indian Scholars will say it is
Buddhism they worship sarasti Buddhism
they worship Lord Ganesh Buddhism they
worship Lord Shiva Buddhism that's what
they've been teaching you okay now when
let's let's call it Buddhism for the
sake of argument when Buddhism entered
Tibet what happened to Bon nothing
happened to Bon the native religion it
still
exists and today everybody in Tibet
whoever still can quietly in secret
because the Chinese don't want this to
happen whoever still practices some of
their ancestral
culture they practice essentially both
it's
syncretic so interet you have vajana
Buddhism which is a very very very
Tibetan Tibet specific form of Buddhism
it is different from other vajana forms
of Buddhism it is tantric Buddhism and
there are elements of bone also in that
okay in Tibetan Buddhism and there are
some people who who practice more of
bone and less of Buddhism there are some
people who practice more of Buddhism
less of bond but it's it's a mixture
it's a syncretic mixture just like in
Japan where you have Buddhism Hinduism
that is syncretized with
Shinto and similarly with Mongolia most
people today they have the swastika
which uh and they practice Buddhism Etc
but they also worship thri and they also
worship umay the the Earth mother so
there are elements of the
old uh tradition the tangri tradition
tangri umai tradition and the worship of
your ancestors and Shamanism and the
worship of forest spirits and nature and
all that all of that is syncretized with
Tibetan Buddhism in in Mongolia so when
it comes to dharmic religions they never
elbow anything out they simply
intermingle and and create something
even way more Rich they create something
richer and even even nicer you know
that's what happens you see that
everywhere wherever you have Indian
traditions outside of the Indian
subcontinent
if you look at Indonesia if you look at
Bali today they have a very very cute
form of Hinduism which is very very uh
distinctively balines very distinctively
local and when you had the majapahit
empire in Indonesia which was the Golden
Age of Indonesia it was Hindu Empire but
a very distinctively Indonesian Hindu
Empire similarly the same thing goes
with Cambodia with with Champa in
Vietnam the Chinese forms of of indic
religions and so on so forth it's all
distinctively local and syncretized with
the local Traditions Indian religions
Indian Indian uh uh Indian traditions
never elbow anything out they simply
Embrace whatever is local and then it it
creates something even richer that's
what happens all
right uh why okay now the next question
is why didn't jism spread to Southeast
Asia uh look J the J path was very
mainstream a long time ago during the
Moria era for for example um our emperor
Chandra Gupta moriam is said to have uh
eventually renounced the throne given it
to his son and Chandra Gupta uh traveled
all the way south to present day
Karnataka or some somewhere around that
region and he became a Jane monei a Jane
Monk
and uh he then chose to undergo Sana
he fasted until he was no more so there
is Jina and today Jina is a very
minuscule part of of Dharma I mean the
population wise but it's still
nevertheless a very important tradition
in Dharma and I'm not sure why it not
did not spread that much so what your
Scholars teachers historians will tell
you is that it is Buddhism that that
spread Eastward right which is not true
it was everything that spread eastwards
I'm not sure how much of G spread
eastwards but you don't find any Jane
frescos or or symbolism in Tibet or
wherever you see Hindu Buddhist imagery
I'm not sure why that is the case but
that's a great question and I don't
think we have the answer right now so I
think uh I will to look into this and
probably historians should look at look
into this and I I wonder why historians
don't have the answer to to this
question but as of now nobody has
answered this question as far as I know
but I'll try and look into this but for
whatever reason uh you don't see J
frescos Jina J paintings Jane sculptures
Etc uh anywhere in Tibet in China in
Korea in Cambodia Indonesia Japan
anywhere or even westwards Central Asia
where everything was replaced because of
the Turks and so on interesting
interesting for
sure okay Priya says uh you say that the
Indian diet is the starvation diet
opposed by the British then what is the
real Indian diet and what should we
include in our diet as the traditional
Indian diet and what did people what did
people used to eat in Ancient India what
was the diet like just curious okay uh
first of all I have not said dear lady
that uh the Indian starvation diet was
imposed by the British you know they
just wanted us to die they wanted our
ancestors to die in these artificially
created famines they created dozens of
artificial famines every year in India
so that it served multiple purposes
first of all it it they forced Indians
to grow cash crops like Indigo Etc
instead of food crops because that those
cash crops brought the British money and
Indian lives were obviously of no value
to them so there was that and obviously
by starving Indians they also ensured
there was no Rebellion because if you
are starving to death how can you fight
so that's why they created all these
artificially engineered famines all
across India dozens every year Millions
died every year I think the British
would have killed I don't know 200 300
million Indians easily over two and a
half
centuries okay and if you divide 200
million by two and a half centuries how
much is that per year what is it 4
million per year that is a very
plausible
number okay
the two and a half
centuries 250 years 200 million it's
it's it's about half a million year I
think the British killed more than that
I think the British killed more than
that it must be 300 million at least 250
million half a billion uh over two and a
half centuries or so now now okay now
coming to the the question uh so the
British did not impose any any diet on
India they simply wanted Indians to die
of starvation but Indians obviously did
not want to die our ancestors wanted to
stay alive so they were forced to adopt
a different diet just carbohydrates just
some just Just Energy see carbohydrates
are a ready form of energy there are
three major types of macronutrients in
your diet protein fat and
carbohydrates and protein is what your
muscles are made of okay you don't eat
protein you won't be able to build
muscles no matter how much you lift fat
is the excess storage in your body
whenever you have excess you eat excess
food it it gets stored in your body in
the in the form of fat uh in some cases
people have to do it if if they live in
polar regions you know polar bears and
and seals they have to eat so much that
that they have a thick layer of fat that
insulates them from the cold for us
humans it's just something we store for
for in case there is a future need for
for energy so you have protein you have
fat and then you have carbohydrates
which is typically your pulses your your
your vegetables your your uh bread rice
all of that stuff cereals all that and
that gives you so when when your body
needs energy rapidly readily it
typically Burns carbohydrates as fuel
and fat is a slow burning fuel
carbohydrates is a fast burning fuel and
so on now the starvation diet I'm
talking about is something Indians had
to do in order to stay alive so carbo is
typically your your pulses your wheat
rice all of that so that's the kind of
diet CB heavy diet that Indians had to
adopt just to stay alive so today if you
look at the standard Indian diet it's
almost all carbohydrates you have rice
you have roties you have patas you have
chapatis uh you have potatoes you have
various vegetables you have dolls and so
on that's what you eat but where's the
protein and we think of it this think of
this as the traditional Indian diet well
that's not the traditional Indian diet
and what was the traditional Indian diet
like in the past well we kind of have
lost uh touch with that there there's
very few records available but I can
show you something okay okay so let us
go to our friend Google and I'm going
to Google a very specific word for
you here's Google and check it out what
I'm Googling
here
manasa so this is an ins okay let's
first of all Wikipedia is not a reliable
source of of information but let's for
the sake of convenience and brevity see
what Wikipedia has to say the Manas the
Manas Solas was also known as
abilash
ABI
lash
abilash chintamani is an early 20 12th
century Sanskrit text composed by the
Kalani chaluka King someswar III who
ruled in presend Karnataka it's an
encyclopedic work covering topics such
as potic governance ethics economics
astronomy astrology rhetoric veterinary
medicine horiculture perfumes food
architecture etc etc etc poetry painting
dance music everything it's an
encyclopedia very valuable now let's see
what it has to say about uh food okay
here has a 12th century fish recipe oh
my God they're eating fish how terrible
right today we would say today Indians
believe that everybody was only
vegetarian in the past our ancestors
only ate vegetables our ancestors were
never meet eaters right that's what we
believe today if you suggest that
ancient Indian Kings ate meat many
Indians will get calized and they will
hate you here is a 12th century fish
recipe cut fishes into pieces wash them
well cook along with Malabar Tamarind
juice sprinkle well with wheat wheat
flour fry in heated oil until Brown add
rock salt sprinkle powdered cardamom and
pepper okay that's one recipe 12th
century fish recipe let's see more let's
see more food and entertainment so it
has foods that are part of Indian
tradition even now like Dosa which is
DOA idika and vaka which is Idi and
V parika which is
pakur D and so on but here is this there
are meat dishes among meat dishes the
text does not include the meat of Cow
Horse elephant parrot peacock or eggs
instead it describes Cuisines based on
pork venison which is deer meat goat
meat and fish among others so your
ancestors my dear friends used to eat
pork they used to eat de meat they used
to eat goat meat they used to eat fish
and various other kinds of meat but they
did not eat cow horse elephant parrot
peacock or
eggs okay so this gives you an idea of
the kind of diet we had I've not read
the entire book in detail but if you
read it you will get an idea and this uh
book I am sure is available there's a u
university of Kent Department of
Mathematics that seems to have this book
which is interesting why does the
mathematics Department have it but let's
take a look at what the book looks like
shall
we uh okay gak's Oriental studies blah
blah blah blah blah uh and so on this is
518 pages so it looks like the real deal
yes and it is entirely in Sanskrit oh my
God a king in Karnataka wrote a book in
Sanskrit how dare he how dare he isn't
he supposed to be
dravidian a king in Karnataka wrote a
encyclopedia in Sanskrit oh my goodness
what about the narrative what about
propaganda
anyhow you see when you look at actual
facts it debunks so many myths it
punctures so many
myths a 12th century King from Karnataka
wrote a gigantic encyclopedia in
Sanskrit and it describes the diet of
the
time
pork deer meat goat meat uh fish there
are recipes from the 12th century and so
on so that's the kind of diet our
ancestors had my friends but today if
you say that Lord this or Lord that ate
deer meat or this meat everybody gets
upset and throws
tantrums the past was a different place
so the starvation diet was not imposed
by by the British it was something our
ancestors had to adopt just to stay
alive they had
to eat things in certain quantities that
they would never have done
otherwise it was done just so that you
stay alive a little bit of rice a little
bit of whatever and just eat to stay
alive whatever is available so whatever
is available generally is not what you
usually would eat that's what happened
so anyhow if you are interested check
out that book The Man the
manasas and you will get uh good
information in there not just about
quing but about so much
more rajat says most of the European
diets include a lot of cheese and meat
and and alcohol consumption is also
quite popular yet they do not suffer
that from that much from diabetes and
other such diseases while bhat is
becoming diabetic by the day why is that
is a question it's because on because of
the carbohydrate heavy diet diabetes is
not caused by fat it's not caused by
protein it's not caused by by meat or
cheese diabetes is caused by an
excessive consumption of carbohydrates
what does it do it it it makes your
liver
fatty and it it increases the deposition
of fat in the pancreas and it kind of
impairs the function of the pancreas the
islands of lagger hands and so on so
forth which turns people into diabetics
and one of the best ways to perhaps
reverse diabetes if it is even possible
some people may may be successful some
people it may not work for them is D is
is is starvation dieting what does it
mean water water water water dieting
water fasting I'm sorry water fasting
you go on a water fast for like three
weeks or something it may completely
reverse your
diabetes it may not work for everybody
and obviously you should consult your
doctor before you even think of doing
something like this but that is known to
work for some people so the point is
alcohol yeah alcohol obviously you drink
too much of that it's going to cause
liver problems and all kinds of health
problems so alcohol I'm not talking
about alcohol but cheese and meat is not
going to cause diabetes it is the
excessive consumption of carbohydrates
on a consistent basis for decades which
causes diabetes all right so cut down on
your roties on your on your idlies on
your dosas on your rice
eat a balanced diet 30% carbohydrates
30% fats 30% protein roughly 33% 33% 33%
roughly and you should have an active
lifestyle you should walk a few thousand
steps a day if possible you should run
every day just for a while 10 minutes is
enough jogging and lift some weights two
or three times a week at
least and so on you do that you won't
have diabetes so India is becoming the
diabetic Capital because we think that
this diet that our ancestors were forced
to adopt the starvation diet we think
it's our traditional diet and we think
it's what we should eat and so everybody
eats what 90% 95% carbohydrates and that
is the reason that's why everybody has a
pot belly everybody is uh skinny fat
and so on also because all Indians are
lots of Indians are sedentary these days
so even if you are eating a carbohydrate
heavy diet but you if you are really
active you would be fine so it's a
conjunction of all these factors that is
that is uh causing this upsurge in the
cases of diabetes in
India okay more questions about food ad
Guru Prasad says why do Asians and
Mexican people
eat a lot of
spices it's about geography it's about
latitudes so let's go to the
map so we have the map here and this uh
line in the center is the equator which
divides the northern hemisphere of the
planet
Hemisphere and India I hope you
understand in the Northern Hemisphere
and then you have the tri the trop of
cancer the Tropic of
Capricorn um which is not visible here
I'm not sure if I bring out that on the
map but I'll not try and do that because
it will take time but um the tropical
regions are the regions which are pretty
warm which are close to the equator and
that's where most of these spices grow
cinnamon cardamom cloves nutmeg Etc
pepper corns all of these aromatic spicy
plants they grow in the uh tropical
regions and the tropical regions uh
India is very much part of the southeast
Asia Indonesia Papua um all of that is
also part of the tropical region Planet
so is ethiop so
is significant part of Africa and so is
also Central America and parts of South
America so you will find that the
climate of Mex Mexico is actually very
similar to the climate of India and the
people of Mexico they look very much
like the people of India this very
similar eye color hair color skin color
and Indians if you go to certain parts
of the US you will be mistaken for
Mexicans and the locals will try to
speak to you in Spanish to show off that
they they know how to speak
Spanish and one faces that in the US
sometimes because of ignorance obviously
but that's what it is uh and so since we
have the we have very similar climate we
have very similar kinds of plants that
go and that's why the Indian Cuisine is
also very similar to Mexican Cuisine in
terms of taste in terms of the
consistency the the texture all of that
the the methods of preparation once
again very similar and also you have
very similar plants that grow in the
region and that's why you have lots of
spices so it's because of the geography
of Central America South America and
India southeast Asia Etc that we have
very similar kinds of Cuisines and we
have lots of spices that we use in our
Cuisines okay CHR motra says why was
Myanmar separated from India and when
and why okay when did that happen and
why do we never talk about this
partition of Myanmar from India so if
you ask a historian why was Myanmar
partition from India they'll say how
dare you call it a partition it was a
separation it was a separation it was
not a partition partition should not the
word partition should not not be used
that's what your your history teachers
and esteemed history professors and
esteemed eminent historians will say
they said don't use the word partition
it was separation so what happened so
this separation was was done in 1937 who
did the separation the British did the
separation did they consult the locals
the people who were affected they did
not consult the people who were affected
so
uh in the 1930s in Burma present day
Myanmar okay where is Myanmar I hope you
guys know but let me put it on the map
just in case we have bhat wassh here the
Indian subcontinent and you go
eastwards and if you go east of Manipur
you have this large country called Burma
it's it's also called Myanmar okay and
the British it was part of the British
ra it goes all the way south and its
neighboring country is Thailand uh and
it also is a neighboring country of
India and Bangladesh and obviously China
as well so uh the British Raj ruled
India as well as Myanmar until the 1930s
when the British decided to separate
Myanmar administratively from India in
Burma there were two political uh
coalitions factions whatever you want to
call it movements one was the separation
League one was the anti-par league Okay
and like the name suggests the
separation League was a bunch of
political outfits that was in favor of
separating Burma from India and the
anti-par league was a number of
political parties Etc Coalition of these
parties which was against the separation
of Burma from India this was in the
1930s so there was a separation League
there was an anti-ep paration League now
before you partition or separate a
country there should be a referendum a
vote right the people should be allowed
to vote for or against it that yes we
vote for separation or no we don't we
vote against separation and whoever gets
more votes that should happen that is
called democracy that's how it should
happen that did not happen I think in
the 1930s which year was it 3235
somewhere around that around that time
look it up my dear friends I don't have
all the dates in my mind in my memory
but it's around 1932 or 1935 there was
an some kind of election that was held
by the British in
Burma a local election and in that
election no party or no Coalition got a
absolute majority but the anti-par
league got way more seats than the
separation
league and if you want to regard that as
a
vote as a referendum then it was clearly
a referendum a vote against the
separation of Burma from
India but the British in
1937 went ahead and administratively
separated Burma from India and Burma has
been separate ever
since so that's what happened it was
done
undemocratically there were the brutal
occupiers of the region so they could do
whatever they want and they did whatever
they
wanted for their own interests they knew
that India's they will soon have to give
some kind of Independence or dominan
status or whatever to India and they
don't want to leave India intact they
wanted to break India into as many
pieces as possible because that suited
their geopolitical their long-term
geopolitical objectives so they
separated Burma from India they
separated uh they eventually engineered
India's
partition uh and much more so that's
what happened and nobody in India knows
about this if you ask a 100
Indians as to how many countries does
India have common borders with I would
say less than 50 will know that Burma
has a common border with India that's
how poor uh our education system is when
it comes to teaching our kids about U
India's geography or the geography of
the Indian subcontinent most people
don't even know what Burma is where it
is that's how bad the education system
is and that's why no one speaks about
this because no one knows about this no
one knows that
Burma I mean no one knows that Burma has
a common board with India that we have
shared history with Burma and and much
more if you ask people what's the uh
what is the language in Burma what's the
religion in Burma most people won't know
what it is and what are the customs in
Burma what's the capital of Burma most
people won't know so that's just
unfortunate but that's how it is and
that's why we don't talk about the
partition of Burma from India the
completely completely illegitimate and
arbitrary partition separation of Burma
from India done by the British for the
sake of their own
interests okay let's take a couple of
questions about physics for a change
because I did not do a physics live
stream this this this week so the
question is by sanskritic Yash the
question is each element has its own
wavelength which is distinct from the
rest how different is it within elements
and do isotopes of an element have
different wavelength as well is there a
relation between different elements and
their wavelengths as in do heavier
elements have a higher wavelength Etc is
there a relation to between the
molecules wavelength and the wavelength
of the elements it's composed of and so
on so what is this wavelength that uh
you are talking about I believe I hope
that you're talking about the Compton
wavelength the Compton wavelength is
inversely proportional to the mass of a
particle so let me put that on the
screen count wavelength the formula for
that the equation for the for the
Compton wavelength in case we can find
that okay Compton wavelength
Compton
wavelength all right let's Google that
and I will go to Wikipedia because in
when it comes to science Wikipedia is
more reliable and the the equation
should be right here Lambda is the
compon wavelength it is equal to H upon
MC where H is nothing but the uh the the
plank constant and M is the mass of the
particle and C is the speed of light
okay so that is the compant wavelength
so when it comes to an atom of an
element each atom has its own atomic
mass number right it has it has a
certain amount of mass and each element
of the atom the ele the atoms of each
element have different masses and that's
why they will all have different comp
compon wavelengths so you're right each
element the atoms of every element have
different Compton wavelengths no atoms
of no two elements will have the same
compant wavelength and the larger as you
can see Lambda is inversely proportional
to M as it's very clear right and H and
C are constants so the larger your atom
is going to be the smaller is going to
be the Compton wavelength all right so
an atom of hydrogen if you compare its
Compton wavelength with an atom of
uranium the uranium atom will have a
much smaller Compton wavelength compared
to an atom of hydrogen and that's just
how it is when it comes to Isotopes
Isotopes are uh instances of an element
with different with the same number of
protons in the nucleus but different
numbers of neutrons so the heavier an
isotope the the shorter will it will be
its Compton wavelength and so on so
that's what you have um obviously
there's a relation between a molecues
wavelength and the wavelength of the
elements it composed go off uh for the
reasons that I just outlined and so
that's what it is okay so yes that is
the simple
relation the Compton wavelength is
inversely proportional to the mass of
the particle and each atom the atoms of
each element have different masses and
that's why they have different Compton
wavelengths and when it comes to
molecules the same thing applies if you
have a molecule of H2 then it's going to
have a Compton wavelength which is which
is essentially half of that of an atom
of hydrogen and so on so check it out
check out the the equation for the
Compton wavelength and that will tell
you everything you need to
know the next question is by bhat bushan
and the question is can you explain the
reflection of light at the quantum level
so the reflection of light is when you
have a mirror and you shine a beam of
light in the mirror and it reflects the
light or even if you look at my face
here reflecting light that is over here
I have a light source here and the the
light you seeing from coming from my
face is reflected light okay it's my
face isn't glowing it's not a source of
light the light you're seeing here is
reflected so how does that happen and
the question is how does it happen at
the quantum level so at the quantum
level the reflection of light involves
interactions between photons which are
particles of light and electrons in the
surface of the material okay any
material metal liquid semi liquid
whatever Rock
it is made of atoms and molecules and
there are electrons in these m in these
in these atoms and molecules there are
electrons in on the surface in the
surface of the of the material so the
reflection of light it involves the
interaction between the photons and
these electrons so first of all you have
the photon electron interaction so when
a photon coming from here encounters the
surface it interacts with the electrons
in the atoms of let's say the skin of my
face okay then then these electrons they
absorb the energy of the photon they
become excited they jump to a higher
energy State and then almost
instantaneously these electrons return
to their ground state by re-emitting a
photon with the same energy and
wavelength so there is absorption of
photon and then an emission of the
photon and the electron goes back to its
ground state from an excited state and
the direction of emission the new Photon
which is emitted is emitted in in in a
Direction that follows the law of
reflection the incident angle and the
refle the reflected angle are the same
that's a basic thing in in Optics the
angle of incidence and the angle of
reflection are the same okay so that's
how photons are emitted the reflected
photons are emitted and the exact path
of the photons is governed by quantum
mechanics which is probabilistic so
probabilities determine the overall
behavior of the reflection of light at
the quantum level but um at the
macroscope opic level it behaves just
like you would expect like to behave
from the perspective of Optics so this
is how reflection happens at the quantum
level all
right okay now let's take questions from
the live chat we have some time so
hopefully we'll take a number of
questions from the live chat so
gentlemen and ladies ladies and
gentlemen if you have questions that you
would like to me to ask you would like
me to answer please ask me now in the
live chat
live
chat um um okay fire motivation says
please explain the story of King Baldwin
of Israel and that's something I'm not
very familiar with I don't I obviously
read of this but was a long time ago it
has something to do with the
Crusades and he was called the leper
King he had leprosy he could not show
his face it was disfigured but he was a
very brave man and he fought the the the
the
sarasin the the
Arabs and uh Salah ayubi Etc uh that's
what I can recall I don't have a clear
memory of the details so that's what I
can say right now but maybe I'll read
that up again and maybe we can revisit
that in in a future session of ask
abijit
um that's a question I've taken before
the recently discovered Dyson spheres
there are not recently discovered Dyson
spheres these are potential candidates
that could perhaps possibly be
Dyson fears it's not direct unambiguous
incontrovertible evidence of Dyson fears
it
is candidate stars that could
perhaps be Dyson speres okay but that
their phenomena could also be explained
by other
natural uh processes like they being
superheated gas or something that is
emitting infrared light okay so I have
already answered this in the previous
live stream in one of the last week live
streams in more detail so it is not
direct unambiguous evidence of Dyson
Spar which would if if that is done if
we find Direct unambiguous evidence of
Dyson of of a Dyson Sphere it means we
are not alone in the universe that would
be the greatest news of the 21st century
or maybe the greatest news in the
history of humankind that's not the case
okay so we have discovered I think seven
or eight candidates that seem that
appear to be appear to have some of the
characteristics that one would perhaps
expect to see if there was a Dyson
Sphere there but the what we are seeing
can also be explained by natural
processes all
right
um okay let's see what else do we
have jnit Singh says hypothetical
question if you were to choose a country
to rule as a supreme leader dictator PM
president which which country will you
choose cannot be India I would choose
the most powerful country of them all
the United States and I would obviously
want to be the supreme
leader uh clearly dictator I mean that's
the best possible way right who wants to
be Prime Minister President and deal
with so many minions be a dictator and
deal with the with the best minions who
will obey you without
question and I'm sure that's how it
works in the US there is a deep state or
whatever they call it in unelected
permanently in power group of
individuals and Mr Biden is just a sock
puppet so I would say I would if I had
the choice of ruling a country I would
want to rule the most powerful country
and what form of leadership I would want
to have the most possible the greatest
possible power right because why
not
okay ANUK ANUK Karma says how does a
nation merge with another peacefully and
consensually you would generally have a
a referendum so let's say you you have a
large nation and a small nation and the
small nation there are people in the
small nation some people who have a
desire to uh merge the small nation with
a large Nation okay a completely
hypothetical case so what should happen
what's the right way to go about this
there should be a democratic referendum
in that small nation so everybody every
adult every voting age legal citizen
should be given the opportunity to vote
Yes I voting for merger or no I am
voting against the merger and then you
count the votes and whichever comes
highest you do
that and if the majority votes for
merger you merge if the majority votes
against the merger you don't merge that
is something that will happen peacefully
and consensually and democratically so
that's generally how it should happen
John says time for AC opinion should one
identify as a Hindu first or as an
Indian well historically Hindu Indian
was the same
thing so if you if you consider India to
be a civilization then if you're Indian
you're Hindu and if you're Hindu you're
Indian that's how I would see it I'm
sure lots of people will disagree and
please feel free free to disagree I am
not imposing any uh anything on you it's
simply my personal
[Music]
opinion
um sorab says please recommend some
books on Indian to read on Indian
politics for a beginner I have not read
a single book on Indian politics so
could not recommend
anything um I have read books about
everything except for Indian politics I
do you see me talking about Indian
politics about what Will what's going to
happen in this state election or who
will Who will win how many seats in that
that assembly I don't speak about that
because I'm not an expert in that I'm
not interested in that so I
can't offer you recommendations about
Indian politics sorry apologies for
that refreshing spot says has the West
interfered in recent Indian elections is
this the region reason for the loss in
seats for the BJP has the West
interfered in the recent Indian
elections yes it
has is that the reason for the loss in
seeds for the BJP I can't say
not sure possible but can't say for sure
but they certainly have been interfering
they've been trying their best to
interfere not just in this election but
they've been trying to interfere within
India and in India's political process
for a very long
time much more than a decade let's say
much more than a
decade an is talking about yesterday's
Cricket final which we won I'm very glad
I had changed yesterday's live stream
timing so that everybody including
myself could watch the final match the
question is by anch is India won what
were your views when the South Africans
needed 30 from 30 there was a point when
South Africa needed 27 runs from 28
balls it was a match that was as good as
won for South Africa and as as good as
lost for India and from there I don't
know how India managed to win it is a
miracle so incredibly pleased that we
showed that mental fortitude that we
never gave up they had six wickets in
hand they needed 27 runs from 28 balls
JP boom what a
bowler I think he's the best white bow
bowler that I've seen I have seen wakar
and Wasim the champions of ball
tampering so okay let's not compare
those guys with bumra today there are so
many cameras you can't do ball tampering
no matter what Mr inzimam hak says come
on eny you it's under you that everyone
did ball tampering you and and Imran
Imran obviously was the was was the
shahen Sha of ball tampering with
bottled caps and whatnot Imran Khan
former prime minister of Pakistan
currently under house arrest or whatever
so I don't want to compare JB bumra with
individuals like Wasim Akram and vakar
unes the champions of bald dampering so
I think bura is superb fantastic and
obviously AR and and hardik Panda hardik
P has got been through a lot ha love him
whatever he did his he did the job I
really really appreciate what he did
yesterday so everybody pulled their
weight especially the three the three
fast Bowlers it was a terrible pitch for
spin bowling not the ball wasn't
spinning at all it wasn't biting wasn't
jumping so and akar Patel still he
managed to get the Wicket of fist stubs
so I think overall everybody pulled
their weight it was a it was a match
that was won by our
Bowlers um I'm not criticizing any
batsman or everything thing you know you
know things happen but the bowlers did
the job and Su Kumar y that catch the
first ball of the final over under that
much pressure he pulled off that catch
incredible so overall great job I was
very pleased I and I kind of felt sad
sad for the South Africans one of my
favorite non-indian cricketers is
Henrick Classen tremendous guy I have
been seeing him I've been ad I have been
an admirer of his since what 2017 2018
when India played them in South Africa
you know chahal and and Kul were
youngsters then and hanik Classen he you
know I think it was his first series he
he did a great job even then and
recently he played a tremendous Innings
against Australia I don't know 180 Plus
or something tremendous Striker I really
appreciate that guy I felt sad for him I
felt sad for Miller but hey my nation
first so I'm I'm really pleased uh so
I'm pleased that Rohit Sharma could go
out on a high his first T20 World Cup he
won 2007 which I watched and his last
220 World Cup he also won good for him
good for kie he also retired great job
over the years great for jja who also
retired and great for dravid he never
got got to win a trophy on his own but
you could see the emotions coming out
yesterday the kind of emotions I saw
from DVID only once before which was in
2001 when he scored 185 against
Australia alongside lakman who scored
281 anyhow so yeah I was very pleased
with the what happened
yesterday okay
um Aruna vakal says can Cricket become a
global sport in the coming decades I
think if the Americans adopt it it could
become a global sport because the rest
of the world Apes the Americans so if
India can manage to make U make America
adopt Cricket it could become one of the
global Sports even without that it's one
of the global Sports because I think
it's only second to football and the
number of people who watch cricket
matches I think because of India's
enormous gigantic population
mainly
uh so I think if the Americans can be
made to adopt Cricket it could become a
global Sport and America the US team did
well recently didn't they they've
defeated Pakistan would you believe it
so yeah
great uh Arian Johan says will India
legal as marij marijuana I'm is
marijuana illegal I think it's illegal
um it's it's semi-legal or something
there is a quantity if you
have Mar you want to below that quantity
I don't know five grams 10 gram whatever
it maybe I have not aware then I think
nobody does anything about it but if you
have in your possession more than that
then you may be in trouble legally you
may be arrested or something like that
and so on I'm not sure what the exact
laws are I think I don't know why
marijuana was made illegal in the 80s or
whenever it was because it's been a
traditional Herb in India used by
Indians for thousands of years and for
various purposes it's not a recreational
drug in India it's part of uh tradition
religious tradition you know people eat
what bang or whatever on certain day
shivaratri Etc so it's part of India's
religious tradition so I think it's kind
of semi-legal espe and especially on
certain days shivaratri ET the cops
won't bother anybody they may also
partake of it themselves perhaps uh I
don't think it should be made illegal
it's it's a it's a it's a plant it's a
herb it's not a synthetic chemically
created drug is it obviously I'm not in
favor of abusing that right I mean why
do that but if it's part of your
tradition it should not be illegal
especially if you it is being used
responsibly
so kind of complicated but um I don't
know what the government's attitude
towards this is I think in India the
governments they typically simply copy
what the West does and that's why it's
currently illegal
above a certain
quantity okay what else do we have what
other questions do we
have
um Anu anuka again says when's the
official AC movies and books
recommendation stream I don't think
it'll be a stream I'll may maybe I'll do
a separate video so in the future sooner
rather than later I will do a book
recommendation video Maybe maybe a
bookshelf tour video uh of the books
that I can show you some of the books I
can show you because I've got more books
than this I'm not sure if showing all
the books is a good idea but I'll show a
l large number of books okay I'll do
that maybe I can do a movies
recommendation video as well maybe
recommend my top 50 movies that I can
think of I could recommend some now now
but I'm sure I'll miss many good movies
so yeah I I'll do that in the future for
sure
um rakasi rajaj says why do people of
South America like in Argentina have
white skin uh well you have to look at
the history of the place when it comes
to
Argentina um there's almost no natives
left there because they have all been
um let's say taken care of they no
longer exist uh I think they
spontaneously disappeared from
Argentina you know
uh in the 8th or if you go to okay uh if
you go to uh Northern Northeastern
England there place called holy Island
where is it let me search for it is it
here where is Holy Island come on man
Lind this F
oh come on Lind this
F oh yeah here we are this place is
called holy Island all right and here we
are and there is an Abby there which is
now in
Ruins and this is
stuck my point is there is an Abby over
here which is uh where is Linda far oh
yeah Castle
and where's the
Abby and the point
is some or 9th century what happened is
that a group of
Vikings
Vikings rescued the treasures of this
Abby because the Abby had somehow
spontaneously caught and monks somehow
spontanously died so the Vikings they
very selflessly rescued the treasures
the gold and the treasures from lindis
farm so I think something similar
happened when the white arrived there
selflessly that the natives had somehow
spontaneously died
away and that's why whoever is left in
Argentina they have white skin because
when the white people arrived in artina
the natives had spontaneously died and
left their land behind so something like
that happened probably that's what I
would
say fire motivation says what could be
the most probable result of the the
upcoming US
elections once again uh yeah I can talk
about probabilities I can't make
predictions I think the Democrats will
win I think Michelle Obama could be the
next president of the US or Hillary
Clinton whoever is the the Democratic
candidate in November I think I I kind
of
doubt if I'm doubtful that Trump will
win simply because the whole system is
geared against him he may be the best
candidate for the US Perhaps Perhaps but
he I think it's less likely that he'll
win it's my Michelle Obama who most
likely would win or whoever is the
Democratic candidate I don't think it's
gonna be Mr Biden or or Miss Harris
Kamala Harris so that's what I think
Could Happen obviously I could be wrong
I not in the business of making
predictions I'm just saying this is what
I think could be more probable than the
the other alternative
uh mad
Madara I don't know what it means says
can we have a Japanese history
special I could do that it's I I'm big
fan of Japan they have a very rich
history going going back to two and a
half thousand years at least minimum so
yeah if you if there is a demand for it
I could do a special on that but I'm not
sure how many people would be interested
like when I do my science live streams
it's what's the kind of ership I have
one fifth of what I have on other days
if I do Japan will it be like that so I
don't know I could do that it's
something that I am certainly interested
in so I'll see I'll consider
that uh arunav Kalita says do you agree
with the views about Oso expressed in
the Netflix documentary Wild Wild
Country well I haven't seen that I
haven't watched the documentary so I
don't know what the views are that have
been expressed in that documentary
uh I think my views about Osho is are
that he was a very interesting person a
very very intelligent very sharp person
not sure how spiritually or
or Advanced or whatever he was maybe he
was I don't know and I think that he was
brought down by his own but the people
he trusted by some of the people he
trusted uh some would say it was
Sila ma Anand CA who did that who who
kind of uh well engineered his downfall
some would that's the allegation some
people would make some people would say
something else overall it looks like he
lost control of his own movement of his
own thing and that's how everything went
wrong for him in the US that's uh the
sense I get I haven't really studied
Osho in great
depth uh I certainly think I should do
that if I can find some time especially
read something about him on or read read
whatever he has written I'm sure it
would be very interesting i' I've seen
some of his video clips and all
definitely a very very sharp person for
sure okay so this is a question I've
already answered did India use taliban's
Network to kill a Pakistani terrorist in
Pakistan or terrorists in Pakistan a
former CIA agent just claimed that
what's the evidence that she put forth
none so a claim that is made without
evidence can be dis without evidence so
that's what I'll do show me the proof or
show me some proof then I'll take it
seriously
um okay
kosal QT says thank you sir uh I want to
okay my question is
where where the Japanese soldier Samurai
really that strong and disciplined that
they could fight off the Mongolian
invasion
okay so there were two Mong two
attempted invasions by the Mongol Empire
the Chinese Yuan Empire which was the
Mongol Empire two attempted invasions of
Japan uh by the Mongol Empire and at
that time the Mongol Empire was ruled by
Shri kubl Khan the grandson of the great
sh chingis Khan okay two attempted
invasions by kubl Khan and there was a
landing I think in tsushima let's go to
the map M and discover where the island
of tsushima
is so let us get rid of the lindis far
let's go Japan where is
tsushima okay
so I'll just uh ask the map thing itself
TS u s h i m a
sushima so this is the island of
sushima and this is where the landing
happened and obviously Japanese fought
the Mongols here but what really
happened
in in both the
invasions is that the Mongols they uh
attempted an invasion by
Ship by launching an armada of ships
towards Japan and both times there were
very severe adverse weather conditions
the Japanese call it Kami Kaz the divine
wind which blew off most of the ships
and destroyed the chances of that either
of the invasion fleets could
successfully conquer Japan so that's
what happened uh obviously the samurai
were great warriors and they were very
disciplined they
have they to have some called which is
the way way of the samurai the samurai
code of conduct
which is very similar to the code of
conduct of the Indian rajputs or
whatever you know Warrior it's it's the
way of the Warriors extremely tough
discipline extremely
harsh conditions imposed upon
yourself and so on men women children
anybody who was in that class of people
the samurai the Warriors they lived that
lifestyle very harsh very hard life very
disciplined life u a very strict code of
conduct very strict code of honor
constant training constant practice and
and much more loyalty towards your
overlord and so on so forth so yes they
were great warriors for sure but the
Mongol invasion failed both times
because of very strongly adverse weather
conditions
storms amik Kaz divine
wind okay let's
take Malik said says classified books
review please haha that um we'll do book
review we we I'll do a book bookshelf
tour for sure um classified will will
think about
that uh okay let's take maybe one or two
more
questions okay the question by three
ways S2 is was pre-islamic Arabia ruled
by
vikramaditya there is zero evidence of
that zero z e r o zero evidence some
claims have been made by uh a writer
called Oak
okay so which Oak was it I don't
remember which Oak it was but he made
some Claim about some poem written about
vikramaditya or something well there's
no evidence of that so a claim that's
made without evidence can be rejected
without evidence as simple as that so
there is zero evidence that pre-islamic
Arabia was ruled by Vikram Adia we know
that there was
polytheism in Arabia before the Advent
of Islam we know that but U was it ruled
by Vi we have no evidence of that
whatsoever okay Arian says please
explain the Balon Wars what was the real
reason who was behind it and who was
Slobodan milosovic look if you want me
to talk about the Balkans I cannot
explain that in two minutes or five
minutes or even 10 minutes Balkans the
Balkans are a very very very complicated
region of I can show you where this
region is it's the Earth Wild
okay you know
R sorry Italy Italy looks
right and if you cross the atic sea to
the east of Italy you have balans the
Balkans Slovenia Croatia BOS Bosnia
heroina Serbia monega Albania
Montenegro uh Albania North
Macedonia Kosovo
bulgar in could con this region it has
an extremely complex complicated
history see what I can say in very brief
is that after the breakup after the
dissolution of the USSR uh the Balkan
region the Yugoslavia the nation of
Yugoslavia which was a part of the
Soviet block the uh the US NATO they
made it a point to disintegrate that
Nation to show that we are now in charge
and we'll do whatever we want so
Yugoslavia was broken up and all these
little nations came out of that Serbia
Croatia uh Montenegro so and so forth
and then there
were these wars these old conflicts
reignited the SEC the first world war
also started in the Balkans by the way
so I I will not be able to explain this
over here I would need a 30 minute video
at least to explain what what the whole
thing is slowo than milosovic is an
alleged war criminal that's what they
say long story so I can't give you the
answer right now I would need a much
longer amount of time to explain that
but yeah it's it's a it's a pertinent
question for
sure maybe one or two
questions mcloven says do you think
marriage is worth it in modern times
especially for men I think the entire
system whether it's in the west whe
whether it's in India is kind of geared
against men so men can be victimized and
the law will the law and the entire uh
system will
stand against men of wom and then men
have to suffer so is it is marriage
worth worthwhile in modern times for men
I think it's worthwhile if you can find
the right partner finding the right
partner is obviously very difficult it's
a choice it's a life it's a decision in
life that will either make or break you
difficult historically you could take
you would take the help of your elders
of your family who would do the due
diligence looking for partners and then
you would know that you are marrying the
right person that was called an arranged
marriage and that is now a taboo thing
oh my God how how regressive arranged
marriage yeah okay then you go and find
your own partner in a random fashion and
then see what happens to you and
obviously these days everything is
influenced by the West so there is so
much more promiscuity in India and
everybody has multiple partners or a
string of Partners and all that I think
there is there is
regrettable uh there is no I I don't see
what fun there is in that but that's
just what it is today so things are
bad and uh it's the system is geared
against men for sure so I think it is
still worthwhile to have a family to get
married and have children it's one of
the most important things that you can
do but yes the choice of partner is is
something that will either destroy your
life or or make your life so you got to
be very careful in that that's what I
can say times keep on changing and
circumstances change sometimes it's
easier sometimes it's harder right now
it's harder for
men okay I think we are almost at the
end let's see if I can find one good
question that I find interesting really
interesting
um K nwat says why is kalari payu not as
famous as Kung Fu or other martial
arts Kari payu is more like a performing
art not like a martial art it's more
like a dance a hybrid of a dance form
and a martial art form not really a
combat sport there's open open hand
striking open hand
striking you got a punch right so this
I'm sure there's multiple reasons some
people claim that kalar P is the origin
originate is the is the root or the
originator of kung fu
there's no evidence for that either so I
don't know but uh it's it's not that
much of a combat sport as the way kung
fu is if you if you were to have a
matching match of styles Kung Fu against
kalaru or karate against kalari payu or
KRA Maga against kalari payu I don't
think kalari payu will come out to be as
effective will come out on top it's more
of a performing art than a martial art
that's how I see it
obviously people will disagree with that
also but that's just the way it
is
okay are we done do we
have do we have anything
else uh do we have lots of other
questions but uh what could I take as a
last
question
um okay I I okay banku Nat Singh says
how would you summarize Our World Cup
victory yesterday I think it was
wonderful it was
glorious and uh they certainly did raise
your raise their standards and I would
urge you all to do the same DJ kamut
says why are you ignoring me sir I just
saw your thing just now I'm not ignoring
you okay I'm not ignoring you there are
thousands of people on the live
stream it's hard to P hard to notice one
person out of that please don't take it
personally if I don't see your
questions all
right Mani says how do you remember so
much stuff what do you do in your
leisure time I don't have Leisure Time
how do I remember stuff I remember stuff
that interests me I don't remember stuff
that I have no interest in so I only
speak about what I find interesting okay
that's just how it is you watch movies
I'm sure people watch movies and they
remember the entire stories and I'm sure
you remember the entire story Arc of of
your favorite TV series or whatever TV
serials so you can remember so much
right because you find it interesting so
similarly there are things I find
interesting and I remember that you ask
me stuff about things I have no interest
in I will remember nothing of that even
if I may have studied that that's how it
is uh yeah okay I'm going to end this
now we have crossed two hours so it's a
good time to end this particular live
stream next week there could be some
changes to the schedule I still don't
know for sure but I will let you know as
as soon as I have some understanding
maybe I will release three podcasts next
week and have maybe few live streams I
will let you know as soon as I have some
clarity okay until then I'm going to end
this and I'm we're going to meet very
soon whenever it happens so take care
take care of yourselves and keep raising
your standards as always I'll see you
very soon bye